exactmetrics.com 2019-11-15

# Privacy Policy - ExactMetrics

Your privacy is very important to us. At ExactMetrics we have a few fundamental principles that we follow:

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. (We can’t stand services that ask you for things like your gender or income level for no apparent reason.)
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of our site.

Monster Insights LLC (“ExactMetrics”) operates several websites including ExactMetrics.com, MonsterInsights.com, and others. It is ExactMetrics’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

**Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, ExactMetrics collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. ExactMetrics’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how ExactMetrics’s visitors use its website. From time to time, ExactMetrics may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

ExactMetrics also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on our blogs. ExactMetrics only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

**Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors to ExactMetrics’s websites choose to interact with ExactMetrics in ways that require ExactMetrics to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that ExactMetrics gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who comment on our blog to provide a username and email address. Those who wish to receive ExactMetrics updates via email, we collect their emails. In each case, ExactMetrics collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with ExactMetrics. ExactMetrics does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

**Aggregated Statistics**

ExactMetrics may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, ExactMetrics may monitor the most popular pages on the ExactMetrics.com site or use spam screened by the Akismet service to help identify spam. ExactMetrics may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, ExactMetrics does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

ExactMetrics discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on ExactMetrics’s behalf or to provide services available at ExactMetrics’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using ExactMetrics’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. ExactMetrics will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, ExactMetrics discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when ExactMetrics believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of ExactMetrics, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an ExactMetrics website and have supplied your email address, ExactMetrics may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with ExactMetrics and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. ExactMetrics takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. ExactMetrics uses cookies to help ExactMetrics identify and track visitors, their usage of ExactMetrics website, and their website access preferences. ExactMetrics visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using ExactMetrics’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of ExactMetrics’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**Business Transfers**

If ExactMetrics, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that ExactMetrics goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of ExactMetrics may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

**Ads**

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by ExactMetrics and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

**Google Analytics**

ExactMetrics is the second-most popular Google Analytics plugin for WordPress. Our goal is to help make analytics easy for users by showing them how visitors find and use their website from inside their WordPress dashboard.

ExactMetrics Google Analytics application uses the Google Analytics Reporting API to gather analytics about your website and present them in an actionable way via charts, graphs and tables inside your WordPress dashboard to any user with administrator level privileges on your website.

ExactMetrics discloses client Google Analytics information with prior user consent only to those of its employees, contractors, and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on ExactMetrics behalf or to provide the services available at ExactMetrics websites (ii) and to provide necessary technical support for our services.

You can learn about the use of Google oAuth permissions [here](https://exactmetrics.com/google-permissions-for-oauth/).

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, ExactMetrics may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in ExactMetrics’s sole discretion. ExactMetrics encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
